Tung D. Nguyen

in tungnguyen21, O tungnguyen1234 tdn84d@mail.missouri.edu (765) 307-8028

I am completing my dual degrees in mathematics and physics with a 4.0 GPA and with strong academic achievements. I have held important research positions involving applications to optimization, artificial intelligence, especially machine learning (ML) and reinforcement learning (RL), and quantum computing (QC). I have strong programming skills with three years of experiences and am looking for a position in which I can strengthen technical skills and can produce strong research outcomes from cutting-edge research at private sectors.

Education

University of Missouri - Columbia, Columbia, MO

Expected 2021

- B.S. in Mathematics and B.S. in Physics, GPA: 4.0/4.0.
- College of Arts & Sciences Undergraduate Research and Creativity Activity Program Fellowship, Summer 2020 term, among 6 recipients chosen from 15 applicants.
- Level I Transfer Scholarship award, University of Missouri Columbia (2019).

Wabash College, Crawfordsville, IN

Aug 2017 – May 2019

- Math and Physics double major. GPA: 3.92/4.0.
- Team member, placed 1st out of 64 teams, Alma Michigan Autumn Take Home Math Challenge (2018).
- Wabash College President's Merit-based Scholarship for undergraduate study.

Professional Experience

1. Recommender Systems Student Researcher

May 2020 — Present

Dr. Jeffrey Uhlmann, Computer Science Department, University of Missouri - Columbia, MO.

- Constructed the unit-invariance multi-dimensional scaling algorithm for recommender system's problem.
- Independently showed the algorithm's convergence by proving Kuhn-Tucker conditions for our optimization model.
- Coded the algorithm on MATLAB to predict users' ratings on films from the 1M MovieLens dataset.

2. Scientific Computing Student Researcher

June 2019 — August 2019

Dr. Matthew Zahr, Mechanical Engineering Department, University of Notre Dame, IN.

- Implemented pre-built Finite Element Method codes on topological optimization of cardiovascular stent.
- Did literature review to identify three external forces on arteries, constructed the objective function for one of those forces, and optimized the structure down to 50%.

3. RL Research Volunteer

May 2020 — August 2020

Vietnam RL Research Group.

Trained the playing agents of selected ATARI games with RAM inputs by adapting Actor-Critic Method,
 Recurrent Neural Network, and Attention Mechanism and processing through NVIDIA Tesla K80 GPU by
 CUDA semantics to increase agent's performance.

4. ML Student Researcher

October 2019 – February 2020

Advanced Manufacturing Lab, University of Missouri – Columbia, MO.

- Collected experimental data over 100 journal papers in a team of three researchers.
- Assisted in building ML model by using Multilayer Perceptron and Leave-One-Out cross-validation.

5. Quantum Materials Student Researcher

August 2019 – May 2020

- Dr. Guang Bian, Department of Physics and Astronomy, University of Missouri Columbia, MO.
- Simulated potential materials structures that can be considered for QC applications from searching through two different materials' databases.
- Took leadership on instructing two undergraduate students.

Publications and Presentations

- Tung D. Nguyen, Jeffrey Uhlmann. Canonical Tensor Scaling. In ArXiv e-prints. ArXiv: 2009.01175 [math.NA]. https://arxiv.org/abs/2009.01175, September 2020.
- Tung D. Nguyen and Matthew Zahr. Topological optimization on the cardiovascular stent through compliance, longitudinal, and dogbonning effects. University of Notre Dame, IN, August 2018.
- Tung D. Nguyen and Nhan D. Nguyen, James Brown. *Monte-Carlo simulation of the Helium atom's dynamics*, github: nnguyen19/helium_project. Wabash College, IN, February 2019.
- Tung D. Nguyen, James Brown. Simulation of the 2-Dimensional Ising model, github: 2-Dimensional-Ising-Model-. Wabash College, IN, May 2019.

Technical Skills

Languages and Technologies

- Python (Pandas, Numpy, Seaborn, Matplotlib.pyplot, PyTorch, TensorFlow, Skicit-Learn, Scipy), MATLAB,
 Java.
- Eclipse, PyCharm, XCode, Microsoft Visual Studio.
- Jupyter, Google Colab.

Coursework

Introduction to Probability Theory, Matrix Theory, Partial Differential Equations, Topology, Complex Analysis, Computational Physics on Python, Quantum Mechanics, Introduction to Density Functional Theory.

MOOCs

- Algorithm Toolbox, Data Structures, Neural network and Deep learning, Algorithm on Graphs.

Languages

- Vietnamese (Fluent), English (Fluent), German (Familiarity).